[theme music playing]
[Julio] You're an extraordinary woman.
You showed admirable courage.
Our family is truly grateful
to you, Miss Aguas.
We are forever indebted.
I became a murderer
because of my love for you!
You didn't think about
how that affected Diego.
You killed his best friend!
You wiped out an entire family!
[Jepoy] I found the hitman Emilia hired.
He's alive.
I'll protect you.
I'll never leave your side.
Whatever happens, I won't leave you.
-Consider my investment done.
-Really?
[Ivy] Like what your mother,
the governor said, we're family now.
[Loring] The mayor wants to build
an export zone here
on the land owned by the cooperative!
And that Ivy? She's one of them!
She's an investor!
I want to host a fundraising dinner
-for the congressman.
-Fundraiser?
[Diego] Who gave you the right
to take the cooperative lot?
Those peasants
will be compensated appropriately.
Ivy, I know where they buried your mother.
Where are you? I'm going there.
I don't care about the Ardientes.
Where are you?
[Jepoy] Ivy, you have to face them.
Or your plans will be ruined.
The Ardientes are here.
[Ivy] I want you to remember my face.
I am Ivy Aguas.
And I am vengeance.
[tense music playing]
[Raul] You enjoyed murdering those people.
You wiped out an entire family.
[Emilia] Didn't you start all this?
If you hadn't taken
a liking to that girl's mother,
her father wouldn't have gone against us!
[Arnaldo] I want you
to invest here in Ardiente.
I'm planning to build
an export processing zone
on the property we visited earlier.
[tense music playing]
[Julio] As long as this statue
stands firm in our town…
You will have leadership!
-Viva, Ardiente!
-[townsfolk] Viva, Ardiente!
Viva, Ardiente!
[townsfolk] Viva, Ardiente!
[Julio] Viva Ardiente!
[townsfolk] Long live, Ardiente!
[tense music playing]
You're all murderers.
You're evil!
You killed my parents!
So now I'll kill you all!
One by one. You! You, Emilia.
You had my parents killed.
-[gunshot]
-[screaming]
Emilia!
You bit--
[gunshots]
[groans]
You started all this!
-You bitch--
-[gunshots]
You murderers!
You'll all pay!
-Especially you!
-[gunshots]
[tense music playing]
[sharp inhale]
You all deserve to die.
[tense music playing]
No, Ivy. It shouldn't end like this.
[dramatic music playing]
[gasps]
I shouldn't stain my hands with blood.
Mom and Dad wouldn't have wanted this.
Justice. Not revenge.
Just like what Ms. Prianka told me.
Ivy?
Ivy, is everything okay?
Yes. Yes, Gov.
That's good to know.
Are you nervous for the event?
[nervous sigh]
Don't be.
You're with the most
influential and successful family in town,
so you don't have to be nervous.
Come, let's meet your guests.
Congressman.
Look at your tie!
Let's fix that.
Diego, can you give me a ride?
Wait for me.
Fernan invited us for some…
you know…
[laughing]
-Sure, Uncle! I'll drop you off.
-All right. Thanks.
Not too tight, okay?
Diego…
Are you sure you want to go to this party?
The party is important to Mom.
See? She even sent me some clothes.
[chuckles]
Your mom sure knows how to convince you.
Just so she can get what she wants.
As usual.
But don't worry.
I won't pass up this chance.
I'll keep my eyes and ears open
for any news about Arnaldo's project.
So, how do I look?
You're so handsome? Oh, don't forget this!
You have to wear this
to complete the look!
Oh, right.
My baby's so handsome!
[applause]
Good evening, everyone.
Thank you so much
for accepting my invitation.
For those who don't know me,
I am Ivy Aguas,
the owner and CEO
of Aguas Realty and Holdings, Inc.
The leading realty company in the country.
Poblacion Ardiente has the potential
to become a mega-business hub.
And for the past 18 years,
it boasts a zero crime rate!
It really is inviting and enticing
to business owners like me.
[upbeat music playing]
And I just want you all to know that…
I want to be part of…
Ardiente's progress.
[applause]
Out with the old…
and in with… the new.
New roads,
new bridges,
commercial buildings,
five-star resorts…
the possibilities are endless
for Poblacion Ardiente,
and that is because of…
the brilliance…
[tense music playing]
and diligence of…
our congressman.
I'll go ahead and call him Señor…
Señor Julio.
Señor Julio…
Ardiente.
[applause]
So tonight,
I want you all to know that
in the upcoming elections,
I will support…
Congressman Julio Ardiente
in his bid for the Senate.
[applause]
And tonight,
we are all here…
because of an auction,
which profits will go
to the campaign fund of our congressman.
[applause]
Congressman…
I mean…
Señor Julio…
I hope this is the start
of our partnership.
Like they say in politics,
it's not just about who wins.
Politics is about…
making friends, finding your allies, and…
destroying your enemies.
Everyone…
Let's make a toast
to Congressman Julio Ardiente,
our Señor Julio Ardiente,
and for Poblacion Ardiente…
And for my parents…
Cheers!
-Cheers!
-Cheers.
Cheers.
[Pandoy laughs]
[indistinct chatter]
It looks like they're having fun already.
[man] Don't worry.
I'll write this off your paycheck.
-Hey, save some for me!
-Hey, Pandoy! Diego!
[laughs]
[man] Nice!
[Diego] It seems like everyone's early.
I know. Shot, shot, shot, Diego. Shot.
I can't. I have somewhere else to go.
[Pandoy] Let me chug that down for him.
[laughing]
Here's to an abundant harvest!
To an abundant harvest!
For the Ardientes!
Hold on…
To the land they should've
given us long ago!
Diego here's going to talk to the mayor
and the congressman
to stop the project here.
That's why he's looking sharp,
because he's going to the party.
Don't worry. I'll have a talk with them.
Diego!
Don't listen to Pandoy. You know what?
Attend that party. Who knows?
You might meet the woman for you there.
[man] That's right.
[clears throat]
Or she could be right behind you.
-[man] Nice one!
-Nimfa!
[quiet music playing]
How did you manage to get Ms. Aguas?
[Pablo chuckles]
Julio, if I were you…
I'd be insulted by that question.
[laughs]
I didn't mean to offend you, Congressman.
[chuckles softly]
No offense taken. Um…
If you add two million
to my campaign fund,
I'll forget what you said.
[laughs]
Now, kidding aside.
It was actually Miss Aguas who came to us
and told us
she was interested in investing
in the export processing zone
I'm putting up.
Interesting move.
For a realtor to gamble in a
public-private partnership that…
[huffs]
…is not even her line of business.
I mean, what's in it for her, Julio?
Well, to expand her business, of course.
You know how these things work, senator.
An entrepreneur…
will stick around
an influential politician of one province
to make their business prosper.
[tense music playing]
But just a piece of advice, Julio.
Be careful in dealing with her.
There's something about that woman.
You know what they say.
The butterfly only appears fragile.
[chuckling]
I didn't know you were
a psychic now, Senator.
[chuckling]
But, no really,
I appreciate your advice,
so don't worry.
I know what I'm doing.
I'm Julio Ardiente.
And I don't make mistakes.
[dramatic music playing]
-[man] Cheers!
-[Diego] Nimfa!
-You're back?
-Get in!
My contract in Manila ended.
My dad told me to stay here for now.
[Fernan] Right. Better here
than in Manila all by yourself!
Your mother and I will take care of you!
Wait. Diego, it's getting late.
Miss Ivy's party might be over
by the time you get there!
I know.
Hmm… So, you're going to a party.
-Here, Dad.
-My mom wanted me to go.
[indistinct chatter]
Well, I better go.
I'll update you guys about the project
they're planning to put up here.
-Thanks, Diego!
-Sir, take care.
-Stay safe.
-Take care.
-Uncle. Take it easy.
-Yeah?
You're going to get it from Auntie later.
-He's a lightweight drinker.
-Nimfa.
-He's down in one shot.
-That's not true.
[man] He'll be out cold.
[Pandoy] No, I won't.
-I dare you.
-All right then.
-[men laughing]
-[indistinct chatter]
-[man] Go on.
-[Pandoy] All right. Here we go.
[indistinct chatter]
[Ivy] We're going somewhere
after the party.
I want to see my mother.
[indistinct chatter]
Joan. Thank you.
-Mrs. Castro.
-Hi.
If you win the bidding,
I'll personally give you a tour.
Thank you, Ms. Aguas.
You know,
what you're doing for Julio is nice here.
But… I advise you
Advise what, Mrs. Castro?
Oh! Ah… Ma'am. Nothing, Gov. It's nothing.
Mrs. Castro…
when you say nothing,
it means there is something.
Uh…
Gov, I'm sorry.
It was just a harmless comment. Sorry.
That's good to hear, Mrs. Castro.
You know,
spreading rumors
is like spreading infectious diseases.
And do you know what should be
done with infectious diseases?
They should be eradicated!
You know, because I don't
want my constituents to fall ill.
[tense music playing]
Excuse me.
Oh!
Did I just say something wrong?
[Emilia] Hmm…
Truth must have hurt.
You know, sometimes,
it's so hard being honest.
You're right, Governor.
There aren't many honest people anymore.
Like with men.
They cheat so blatantly.
[tense music playing]
That's why I don't easily trust men.
Men these days.
If there are men that I do trust,
they would be Congressman Julio and…
Mayor Ardiente-Torillo.
They are respectable
and won't ever trick you.
[Natalie] Exactly, Ivy.
But apparently,
no matter how faithful your partner is,
there are just some women
who can't stop until they ensnare them.
That's why, Natalie…
keep your eyes peeled,
because someone might snatch him away.
Speaking of which…
the auction is about to start.
Excuse me, I better get ready.
[tense music playing]
[sinister music playing]
What a waste of money.
They should've donated it to the farmers.
I'm sorry!
Are you okay?
[tense music playing]
Oh, hi.
-Hi.
-What's up?
I guess we arrived too early. Right?
It's kind of boring here.
We can go out, if you want.
[sinister music playing]
Thanks for the offer,
but I'm with other people.
I'll go ahead.
My dear husband.
-There you are.
-Yeah.
And who are these quaint-looking models?
Oh, your dress looks beautiful,
ma'am. Where did you buy that?
Thank you. I got this
from a French designer.
Sadly, she passed away. You know why?
She flirted with someone else's husband.
-Get it?
-[Raul] Let's go?
-We have to go.
-Yeah. Let's go, honey.
Oh!
By the way, it was nice meeting you both.
Take care out there.
[Emilia] Let's go.
[instrumental theme music playing]
Let me put these on you, dear.
Ivy…
are you sure…
you're okay?
I want to go to my mom.
I want to visit her.
I know you're devastated, Ivy.
Let's just stop this party.
I'll ask them to leave.
I'll just tell them that
you're not feeling well, okay?
Dear?
If only we could.
But I have to push through.
I need to do this as part of my plan.
Ivy, in that case,
let out all your frustrations.
Don't keep it in.
Or else, it'll eat you alive.
Thank you, Nanny.
For always being there.
I can do this, right?
Yes, dear.
["Wildflower" by Arnel Pineda playing]
♪ Let her cry ♪
♪ For she's a lady
For she's a lady ♪
♪ Let her dream ♪
♪ For she's a child
For she's a child ♪
♪ Let the rain fall down upon her… ♪
[flamenco music playing]
[Joan] Ladies and gentlemen,
Ms. Ivy Aguas.
[flamenco music playing]
[applause]
Ladies and gentlemen,
let the auction begin.
Our first property is in Batangas.
A beautiful two-story townhouse
situated by the sea.
It has three bedrooms,
two toilets and baths,
and wrap-around balconies.
Bidding starts at five million pesos.
Five point five.
[Joan] Five point five million pesos
for Mrs. De Castro.
Do I hear
six million?
-Six million.
-Six million for Mrs. Ramos.
Anybody bidding higher?
Going once? Going twice?
Sold to Mrs. Ramos for six million pesos.
Congratulations, ma'am.
[applause]
[Joan] We're very proud
to present our last property on the list.
A secluded bed and breakfast
overlooking
the cool mountains of Baguio City.
It boasts a café, a spa,
and a botanical garden.
Bidding starts at 30 million pesos.
-Thirty million.
-Thirty million for number seven.
[man] Thirty-two million.
Thirty-two million for number five.
Thirty-five million.
Thirty-five million for the good senator.
Thirty-seven million.
Thirty-seven million, Mr. Romero.
Thirty-eight million.
[Joan] Thirty-eight million.
Anyone bidding higher?
Thirty-eight million. Going once.
Going twice.
Sold to our dear Mr. Senator.
Congratulations, sir.
[applause]
Thirty-eight million pesos
for such a small property?
That could buy hectares of farmland.
[tense music playing]
[Ivy] Thank you to everyone
who bid and won.
This is a big help
for Congressman Ardiente
in his bid for the Senate.
[applause]
Congressman.
Ivy, if you don't mind,
could I say a few words?
[Ivy] Um, sure.
I'll hold the mic for you.
My friends, I would first like
to thank Ms. Aguas
for insisting on organizing
this fundraising event.
This is a big help not just for me,
but for all of us in Poblacion Ardiente.
[applause]
And aside from that,
I would like to personally thank
Ms. Aguas…
for her investment
in the export processing zone
that will rise in our town.
This project will be a big step
in further promoting Poblacion Ardiente
as the fruit and vegetable
export capital of our country.
[applause]
And of course,
we are just waiting for additional funding
to start the clearing
operations on the lot
where this project will rise.
And at this point,
not that I would like to put…
Ivy on the spot, but…
Can you further extend your assistance
to Poblacion Ardiente?
[somber music playing]
[chuckles]
Señor Julio…
Señor Julio knows that…
I just can't resist him!
[laughs]
[Ivy] Of course, I will.
Let's give Ivy a round of applause!
[applause]
Ladies and gentlemen,
Ivy is such a generous person,
and she really loves Poblacion Ardiente.
With the blessing of what Ivy just said,
our town's export processing zone
is definitely a go.
Thank you, Ivy. Thank you very much.
[applause]
[tense music playing]
We have a lot of projects…
Miss, excuse me.
-[Ivy] Um…
-Excuse me.
Let me guess…
-Mojito?
-That's too weak.
I like it on the rocks.
Oh. You really are something
else, Ms. Aguas.
You know what you want.
Thank you for investing
in our project, by the way.
I don't need your thanks.
I invested a lot. That means, Mr. Mayor…
I'll expect a lot in return.
I know what you mean.
But can we not talk about business now?
-Mr. Mayor--
-No, let's just…
dance.
After all…
[sensual music playing]
You're mesmerizing when you dance.
Stop it.
If you don't want to be humiliated,
stop it, Mr. Mayor.
-Ivy! Ivy!
-Mr. Mayor, what is your problem?
Excuse me. What's going on?
I need to talk to you, Arnaldo.
Ms. Aguas.
I appreciate all the attention
that you've been giving my boyfriend.
You and I both know he is
so powerful and he's so handsome.
And apparently,
every other girl in this town
wants a taste of him.
But you know? My boyfriend is not a book
nor is he a toy…
that can be borrowed or shared.
My boyfriend…
is mine.
Just mine.
Do you understand?
Completely, Natalie.
Now listen to what I have to say.
You can have Arnaldo.
He's all yours.
I don't like secondhand things.
Because I like my toys brand new.
[tense music playing]
[tender music playing]
[phone chimes]
[Jepoy] It's too dangerous.
[Ivy] I want to see her.
Take me to her.
I need to talk to Grandpa.
What will happen to the farmers?
This is a huge problem.
[Ivy gasps]
[instrumental theme music playing]
[theme music playing]
[young Ivy] Hey kid, don't jump! Hey!
[young Diego screaming]
Help!
[young Ivy] Hang on!
-Careful, okay?
-Just hold on.
-Oh.
-[both chuckle]
[young Ivy laughs]
["Sa'Yo" by Silent Sanctuary playing]
[snickers]
[huffs and chuckles]
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, Mr. Torillo.
I'm sorry for laughing. Um…
I was caught off guard. Uh…
What are you doing here, Mr. Torillo?
Well… what are you doing here?
Why aren't you inside? It's your party.
Uh…
I needed to take a call.
It's noisy inside.
I'm going back to the party now.
Excuse me.
Miss Aguas. Hold on.
How will you benefit…
from investing in Ardiente?
Never mind. I already know the answer.
Ms. Aguas!
Senator.
Thirty-eight million.
Ah.
Thank you, Senator. You're too generous.
Well, Julio and I are good friends.
He helped me win in the last elections.
And now it's my turn to help him.
Your friendship must run very deep.
[chuckles]
Let's just say that…
he knows me as well as I know him.
We protect each other.
[tense music playing]
Oh.
Your duo must be difficult
to beat, Senator.
[chuckles]
Don't worry, Miss Aguas.
I won't get in the way…
of your plans.
I'm sorry. Plans?
[chuckles]
Don't play coy with me, Miss Aguas.
[scoffs]
You wouldn't invest that much money…
for nothing.
I know you're up to something.
[tense music playing]
Until we get the money
I made Miss Aguas hand over,
we still have to reel her in.
Why don't you invite her
for breakfast tomorrow at home?
So we can
finalize the papers for the projects.
I will, Papa. Leave it to me.
[Ivy] Senator.
You know us entrepreneurs too well.
We're persuasive.
-And clever.
-Oh.
-[Pablo chuckles]
-When we do business. [chuckles]
I must say,
you're a very
interesting woman, Miss Aguas.
[both chuckling]
I envy Julio.
You chose him first.
But just a fair warning.
Be careful around Julio.
He's clever too, like you.
[both chuckling]
Senator,
watch your words.
The congressman's nearby.
I might tell on you.
[both chuckles]
-I like you, Ms. Aguas.
-And I like you too.
Senator, I want to know more
about you and…
Congressman Julio.
I hope we can talk sometime.
[chuckles] Sure.
-[chuckles]
-Anytime, Ms. Aguas.
[tense music playing]
Wait, where are Arnaldo and Diego?
There he is.
Diego.
Where's your necktie?
I took it off, it's choking me.
I don't care if it's choking you.
This is a formal affair.
You should look formal.
Being with those farmers continues to
diminish your breeding.
Since you mentioned the farmers,
I'm concerned about
what you said earlier, Grandpa.
What will happen to the farmers
if you continue the project?
-Then they'll leave.
-But, Grandpa--
Enough.
Let's just talk about that
when we get home, okay?
Where is Arnaldo?
[Emilia] He should be here, Papa.
-Oh.
-[Arnaldo] Where are you going?
We're going home.
[speaker id] Let's go.
Papa, Arnaldo, go ahead.
I'll just ask Ivy something.
-Go ahead.
-Okay.
All right.
-[Carlotta and Emilia shrieking]
-Mom.
Excuse me, Senator.
-Sure.
-[Ivy] Joan?
[screams]
Emilia!
Not this again.
Ma'am…
-You okay, Mom?
-Ma'am, I'm sorry.
[shrieking]
-[Carlotta] Ouch!
-[Emilia gasps]
-Ouch! My hand!
-Careful, ma'am.
-[Carlotta yelping]
-[Emilia whimpers]
I'll wrap this around your hand
to stop the bleeding.
[Carlotta yelping]
Please bear it.
But you have to clean this later.
Thank you, thank you.
[Carlotta groaning]
[yelping]
-Thank you, sir.
-Nanny!
Nanny Carlotta.
What happened?
Thank you, Mr. Torillo.
What happened? How did it happen?
Ivy, it was an accident!
Your maid spilled hot coffee on me
then slipped on the ground
and hurt her hand!
Look at my skin now! It's irritated!
What if I get first-degree burns?
I have to go see
my dermatologist tomorrow.
Ouch! Ouch, ouch, ouch, ouch.
-[Emilia whimpers]
-[Carlotta groans]
You've got the skin
of a crocodile, Governor.
I'm sure it'll be okay.
You didn't get any cuts.
[tense music playing]
Next time, you be careful.
You know, maids like you
should have presence of mind.
Especially you, you're old already.
Who will hire you?
What will happen to your family?
I mean, you should be thankful
that Ivy's nice.
If you worked for me,
I wouldn't allow this.
Use your head. You're so stupid!
-Mom.
-That's enough, Governor.
I'm…
I'm sorry, Governor.
I'll talk to her myself.
But I'd never entrust…
my house…
and my life…
to anyone I think is stupid.
[exhales sharply]
[music]
I'm sorry. Don't get me wrong.
You know, she should be more careful.
We can also be more careful…
with the words we say.
Right, Governor?
[clears throat]
I'm sorry…
but you may leave.
[scoffs]
Yeah, we better get going.
We should go now.
Oh, by the way, congratulations.
Your event was such a huge success.
We'll go ahead.
Oh.
I shall see you tomorrow,
for breakfast in our house, right?
And don't worry.
My maids…
won't spill coffee on you.
Bye.
[tense music playing]
I'm sorry.
Nanny…
That maid ruined my dress!
Ugh!
I just had this made…
and now it's ruined.
Poor dress.
So disgusting!
It stinks.
It's just stained.
You can always buy a new one.
Excuse me, Raul.
My dress isn't like your women…
cheap and disposable.
Well? Aren't you going to say anything?
You know, Raul,
you're really unbelievable.
You might be forgetting that
I am now the governor.
So please act respectably.
I know it's difficult for you,
but put in some effort.
Gosh.
You know what, Emilia?
I haven't done anything wrong.
I just talked to them. That's it.
So, I don't understand
why you keep running your mouth.
Hey.
Where are you going now?
Why are you packing your stuff?
Are you going to see your mistress again?!
No.
I'll go earn some money
so you can buy a new dress.
What? Ugh!
My dress.
[whimpers]
[somber music playing]
Sweetie.
Dear, that's enough.
Ivy, dear.
You shouldn't let
your anger get the best of you.
You shouldn't have defended me.
Emilia might
want to do something against you.
Your plans will be ruined.
Why wouldn't I defend you?
Nanny, I'm sorry, but tomorrow,
you must go to Manila.
Leave me here for now.
No.
I won't leave you here, Ivy.
Please don't be stubborn.
I don't want those Ardientes to hurt you.
You're the only family I have now.
I… I don't know what I'd do if?
Hush. Dear.
Calm down.
All that anger won't do you any good.
I won't leave you.
Nanny…
-Look what happened to you.
-[shushes]
Ivy…
[tense music playing]
You're okay now, right?
-Mm-hmm.
-Get some rest.
I have to go.
Let's go. Take me to my mother.
But, Ivy…
Take me to her.
-Ivy.
-Get some rest.
Jepoy, let's go.
Well? Let's go!
[tense music playing]
Je--
[somber music playing]
[gasping]
Mom?
Mom…
[crying]
Mom, it's…
Mom, it's me Lily.
It's Lily, Mom.
[instrumental theme music playing]
[crying]
Mom…
[music continues]
[Ivy wailing]
[crying] Mom…
Mom…
Jepoy, what did they do to my mother?!
Jepoy, what did they do to her?
Why did this happen?!
How could they do this to her?
What happened, Mom?
Mom… What happened?
Why did it happen, Jepoy?
[instrumental theme music playing]
[Diego] I still believe there's
hope for this town.
No matter what you do,
you can't change their lives
as long as this family is in power.
[Ivy] I feel nothing but pain,
hatred, and fury, Mom.
I promise you and Dad.
I'll avenge your deaths.
[Ivy screaming]
Governor, now that someone's
openly going against you,
I'm starting to reconsider my investment.
These things started
the moment she came here.
I'll uncover her deepest secrets.
[theme music playing]